Could identical twins get away with
murder?
Identical twins have the same DNA. So,
if one of them commits a murder, which
one goes to prison? [music] When police
run a standard DNA test at a crime scene
and it matches two twins, they're stuck.
[music]
And this has literally happened. In
Germany, two twin brothers were
suspected of robbing luxury [music]
stores. DNA was found, but they both
walked free cuz they couldn't prove who
did it. But, the identical in identical
twins
>> [music]
>> isn't quite right. Monozygotic twins
start with the same DNA, but they don't
stay identical. Every time your cells
divide, copying errors can occur and a
single letter in your genetic code can
get swapped. Across 3 billion base
pairs, twins may differ in roughly five
positions. [music] Now, in the unique
case of twin suspects, scientists can
now use whole genome sequencing, which
reads all 3 billion base pairs to try
and find the differences. But, [music]
these are expensive and sufficient DNA
samples are required to ensure results.
>> [music]
>> If they've left a puddle of their own
blood at the crime scene, great. If not,
tricky. So, in the right circumstances,
being a twin might just keep you out of
jail. Subscribe for more.